I want to buy this plan or that plan. Its
advantages seem to be more. You know what?
Buying a health insurance plan is
not difficult, but choosing the right plan
is a very difficult task. So, to
reduce this difficulty today, we are here
to discuss the top six health insurance
plans in India for the year
2024. We will understand these plans through comparison. These plans are
Aditya Bedla
's Active and Next plan, Care
Insurance's Care Supreme plan, STFC
Arbo's Optima Secure plan,
ICICI CI Loba's Health Advantage Pix
plan, Niva Bappa's Aspire Titanium Plus
plan, and Tata AIG's MediCare Premier
plan. Please note,
I am going to tell you the details of these plans according to the sum insured amount of Rs 10 lakh. So, first of all, let's
talk about the minimum entry age. Minimum
entry age means at what minimum age can you
buy the plan?
Minimum entry age for adults in the plans of Care Insurance, STFC Arbo, Niva Bappa, and Tata AIG.  The minimum entry age for an adult is 18
years and for a child is 91 days.
In Aditya Birla's plan, the adult age is 18 years
and the child age is 91 days for floater and
multi-individual plans and five years
for individual plans.
In ICICI Lombard's plan, the minimum entry age is 18 years
for adults and
91 days for children, for floater and six years
for individuals. Now, let's talk about the sum
insured. The sum insured is the
maximum amount that the insurance company pays to
you at the time of claim. Now here, if we
talk about Aditya Birla's plan, the
minimum sum insured limit is 2 lakhs (
minimum 2 lakhs) and the maximum is 6 crores. In
Care Insurance, the
minimum sum insured limit is 5 lakhs and the
maximum is 1 crore. In ADFC, it is
minimum 5 lakhs and maximum 2 crores. In
IIC plan, it is 5 lakhs (minimum 2 lakhs) and
maximum 3 crores.  For Niva Bappa Spire
plan, it is minimum 3 lakh and maximum 1
crore. And if we talk about the plan of AIG, then
this limit is minimum 5 lakh and
maximum 3 crore. Now let's talk about room
rent. Room rent limit is the
amount that the insurance
company pays for a hospital room per
day. It is different as per the category of the room
chosen. So, if we talk about these plans, then there is no
room range limit here.
Accept One plan which is ICICI
Loba, in its health plan only
single private room will be available to you. If you buy this
plan, now let's no pre-hospitalization. It
means those expenses which
cover the treatments before hospitalization. These expenses are
covered for up to 60 days in all the plans.
Accept Aditya Birlas plan which is
covered for 90 days. Now let's no post-
hospitalization. It means those expenses
which
cover the treatments after hospitalization.  These expenses
are covered for up to 180 days in all plans, except for the
Accept TA AIG plan, which covers 90 days.
Now let's talk about day care
procedures. These are procedures that can be done
within a few hours of the day.
You don't need to be hospitalized for this.
All these plans cover day care procedures, except for the
Accept TA AIG plan, which covers
541 TRII numbers. Now, you must have heard about this feature.
Domise hospitalization means
treatment for any illness or disease at home if the patient is not in a
condition to get treatment in a hospital.
This expense
is covered in all these insurance policies. Talking about modern
treatments, it means treatments that are done
through modern technology, for
example, robotic surgery. These are also
covered in all these insurance policies. Now, let's know about
non-medical expenses.
Expenses like gloves, masks, syringes, etc. are
also covered in all these six plans.
And in Tata AIG plans, this
expense is inbuilt covered up to the sum
insured amount. But in Aditya Birla Care
Insurance, ICICI and VVP plans,
this expense is available as an add-on
which is also covered up to the sum insured
amount. Now let's talk about maternity expenses.
These are the expenses that cover
prenatal delivery and
postnatal expenses of an insignificant pregnant woman. These
expenses are not available in Aditya Birla Care Insurance
and STFC Arbo plans,
but they are covered in III Lo But with a
sum insured amount
maximum of ₹1 lakh. In N V plans, these
expenses are covered up to ₹1 lakh and in Tata AIG,
maternity expenses are covered up to ₹5000000
and for girl child birth, the amount covered
is maximum ₹1000000. Now let's know about it.
No Claim Bonus, which is the next feature,
means that when you do
not make a claim in a particular policy year, the
insurance company offers you a discount in the next policy year.
Care Insurance, ADAC Arbo and TA
AG give you a no claim bonus of 50% each year, which can go up
to a maximum of 100%.
In Aditya Birla, the no claim bonus is 100% every year, which can go up
to 500 and a maximum of Rs 3 crore.
In III Loan Bar, the NCB is 20%, which
is a maximum of 100%.
In Ni, you get a booster benefit where you can carry
forward the unutilized sum
insured amount to the next year with Rs 1500 and Rs
300 per year maximum based on the entry
age. Not only this, you can also get a super no claim bonus,
which is
available only in Care Insurance plans among these plans,
where you can avail 100% super NCB,
every year maximum up to Rs 500 per super
claim.  The bonus works in the same way as a duplicate
bonus. The only difference is that the Super No
Claim Bonus increases your sum insured by
an additional percentage on top of the No Claim
Bonus already applied to your policy. Now let's talk about the
initial waiting period.
You cannot apply for an instant claim after purchasing the policy.
Except in case of an
accident, you have to serve an initial waiting period
to start getting the
claim. So, in all these policies, you get an
initial waiting period of 30 days.
Now let's talk about pre-assisting
waiting period. This is the disease which was
diagnosed before purchasing the policy.
Their waiting period is 36 months in
STFC and Neeva Gappa, 24 months
in ICICI and Tata AIG and 48 months in
Aditya Dal and Care Insurance
plans. Care Insurance plans
also offer the option to reduce it to
12, 24 and 36 months.  Also you have option to
cover medical expenses related to asthma,
diabetes, hypertension from day 31
now let's talk about the last feature which is
specific treatment waiting period where
you have to serve a waiting period for some specific illnesses and diseases
which is
24 months in all these plans so these are the
top plans available in the market and make sure
you go through the plans documents well
and then make a choice to buy the other
queries drop in the comment section and call
on the given number thanks a lot for watching
[sangeet]